RG 004:153, Watertown Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Watertown Probate Court records
1834-1938
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Watertown District)
15 cubic feet
Record books, 1834-1938; Probate files, None.
RG004_153
2011-105
Historical Note
Watertown, Litchfield County, Town established in May 1780, Parent Town: Waterbury
The Watertown Probate District was constituted June 3, 1834, from the Waterbury Probate District. The Watertown Probate District merged with the Woodbury Probate District on January 8, 2003 to create a single probate district. The Woodbury Probate District merged with the Oxford, Roxbury, Southbury, and Washington Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region # 22 Probate District which serves the municipalities of Bethlehem, Oxford, Roxbury, Southbury, Washington, Watertown, and Woodbury.
Town of Watertown, Probate District chronology:
May 1780 - June 2, 1834, Waterbury District
June 3, 1834 - January 7, 2003, Watertown District
January 8, 2003 - January 4, 2011, Woodbury District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region # 22 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, vol. 1-26, 1834-1933. Contact the probate court to access original record books after volume 34. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, None. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2011-105 are numbered from 1-26.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Watertown
Places:
Watertown (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-105, Record books, 1834-1938, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files from 1921-1946 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-4, 6, 9-11, 13-15, 17, 1834-1917, were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The record books in accession 2011-105 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 20, 2011.
Container List
- Record books, 1834-1938; 15 cubic feet (26 volumes); 2011-105
  - Records, 1834-1841 (Volume 1)
    Volume 1 is in two parts: Part 1, pages 1-247, and Part 2, pages 248-514
  - Records, 1839-1849 (Volume 2)
    Volume 2 is in two parts: Part 1, pages 1-252, and Part 2, pages 253-530
  - Records, 1849-1861 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1859-1870 (Volume 4)
  - Orders, 1862-1886 (Volume 5)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1874-1890 (Volume 6)
  - Bonds, 1881-1916 (Volume 7)
  - Orders, 1885-1902 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1887-1893 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1893-1899 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1897-1901 (Volume 11)
  - Orders, 1901-1912 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1901-1908 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1906-1910 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1910-1914 (Volume 15)
  - Orders, 1912-1920 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1914-1917 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1916-1920 (Volume 18)
  - Bonds, 1916-1938 (Volume 19)
  - Orders, 1920-1926 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1920-1922 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1922-1926 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1925-1927 (Volume 23)
  - Orders, 1927-1931 (Volume 24)
  - Records, 1928-1930 (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1930-1933 (Volume 26)